At first, when we started to explore genetic levels,
there was a time when we believed it was everything.
Then, in genetic research,
we realized that only 5 to 10% of genes were actually used.
And everything else, we thought, well, it’s not much.
But then, as progress continued, they realized
the impact of
the environment. And that all these environmental systems can
modify genetic behavior
very quickly. It means you have on a
DNA chain,
you have molecules, you see, a chain of molecules with amino acids
will form...
a genetic codon, which allows for the production of a protein, to structure, etc.
So first of all, we realized that this system is not fixed,
but it continually modifies and adapts.
Just being in another environment,
or an emotional shock, or something powerful can modify it.
You see, when we know anatomy, when we know anatomy in the function given by
endocrinology, we have an impact, as Anthony Schillac said, down to the cellular level,
but even at a global level. And we have a responsibility. We
must be mindful of what
we do, how we touch. You see, that’s a kind of
cellular modeling, you see,
and if you take a cell,
the cell is connected with other cells
by what?
by cells
by small molecules we call intercellular
adhesion molecules
molecules that maintain
so I have a membrane
but in fact what we realized
is that the cell itself has a cytoskeleton
so it has a skeleton too
and this cytoskeleton
is connected to the membrane
up to the nucleus, you see, up to the nucleus, really by lines of
force, precise structures in the nucleus, in the cell, down to
the interior.
Down to the interior.
And from there, we have the very important concept of what we call tensegrity.
In osteopathy, it means that if I touch someone, I
have touched their whole body.
It touches.
It’s a frequency, a vibration that touches the whole body.
Here we see, you see, a cell with the extracellular matrix.
And we see here, you see, this junction between the cell
and the outer part.
It means that what happens here has deep information all the way here.
It means an electric field, an electromagnetic field,
light, temperature...
Temperature, pH, etc. All that, everything that is
mechanical stress, shock, deformation,
hydrostatic pressure, all that influences cellular behavior. So
it’s not
just a small impact, it’s a whole environment that influences the system. We
realized that in the genetic program, we
carry generational impact.
behavior. It means we have been able to observe that if you have
had traumas in other
lives, from your family, your parents, stuff like that, we can
transmit it. And that
in each generation, we can carry, up to three generations, easily,
we can carry
information in our code. And we are here sometimes
to read it.
Freed, at least from three generations, maybe much more. But they have been able to
observe
in genetic studies, in observations, maps, if you will, you see,
things like
this, and in certain readings, suddenly they see an appearance
that will emerge
from the present. They were able to trace back in these observations up to three generations
in a behavior of trauma.
It’s a level of frequency.
It means that your technique will not be a technique, but will be a frequency.
So the presence of elementary particles implies forces in life.
Currently, we recognize four major forces.
The weak force, the strong force, electromagnetic force, and the force of gravity.
The weak and strong forces are nuclear forces,
they are forces that exceed us.
To give you an image, if I were to remove one of
these forces from the universe, it would collapse like a house of cards.
On the other hand, the electromagnetic force, what’s interesting is to see that it
allows interactions of the systems.
So it’s responsible for the binding, it’s responsible for what
allows matter to exist in its form.
So here, the end...
The electromagnetic force is important.
It means that the organism will involve, that it will possess
systems to have these forces within it, to call on these forces.
Because where does the electromagnetic force come from? Where does it come from?
Regardless, it was already there before us.
And at some point, when matter arrives, it needs to have this capacity.
And what is very interesting is to note...
that I will now talk to you
about the beginning here, we call
the polarized man.
The polarized man.
Maxwell's law is very simple.
It says that if you have an electric field,
you always have around
an electromagnetic field.
In other words, if I have an electric field,
around it, there is an electromagnetic field.